R. ALEXANDER KNIPPER

alexknipper@comcast.net · 219-789-7098 · linkedin.com/in/alex-knipper/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Self-driven Computer Science student whose goal in both education and industry is to become familiar with as many concepts of Computer Science as possible through many different experiences and teachings. Passionate and extremely interested in exploring the interactions between people and machines, and how to improve them.

EDUCATION

MAY 2020

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, MATH & NETWORKING MINOR,

INDIANA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

Current GPA: 3.86/4.00

SKILLS

- Proficient in C++, Python, and C#
- Proficient in Windows and Windows Server
- Proficient in Active Directory and IIS

- Experience with Java and Linux systems
- Proficient in Batch and PowerShell Scripting
- Proficient in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

EXPERIENCE

MAY 2019 - PRESENT

DEVELOPMENT OPERATIONS,

SWEETWATER SOUND

Application Developer

- Implementing scalable designs for processing large amounts of data
- Generating templates of commonly used code to improve efficiency
- Keeping and maintaining clean code and content over an extended period of time

AUGUST 2017 - PRESENT

COLLEGIATE CYBER DEFENSE COMPETITION (CCDC) TEAM,

INDIANA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

Windows and Cryptography Specialist

- Working in an incredibly fast-paced, high-intensity business environment
- Practicing documentation in order to make future workflows more efficient
- Developing standard procedures to keep computer systems secure as fast as possible

ACTIVITIES

- Dean's List (2017-Present)
- Cheerleading (2017-2019)
- Cyber Defense Team (2017-Present)
- National CCDC Qualifier (2018)

- Latin Club (2013-2016)
- National Latin Exam Silver Medal (2015)
- National Cyber League (2017-Present)
- VEX Worlds Qualifier (2016)